This is a story about love.
The princess of a certain country fell in love.
The person she fell in love
with was the castle cook.
Theirs was a love between
people of different social classes.
This is off topic, but why
do we say "fall in love"?
Is it because one falls into it unexpectedly
and suddenly, like a pitfall trap?
Not that I would know.
The two of them nurtured their love secretly,
and in time, the princess became pregnant.
Yes, it was the fruit of
their love, so to speak.
"The Princess Without Subjects"
This place is in ruins...
I wonder if there was a war or something.
I didn't hear anything about that, though.
There isn't a single person here...
Still, this is a problem...
Even if I head to another town now,
I probably won't get there
until the middle of the night...
I'll freeze...
This is the only place that
looks like it's still standing...
It looks like no one's home.
I am very reluctant to do this,
but I have to do what I have to do.
Please excuse the intrusion.
Who are you?
I feel alive again.
It was cold outside, wasn't it?
Yes.
At any rate, I didn't think anyone lived here.
I didn't think anyone would come here, either.
Where did you come from?
From a faraway, distant land.
I'm a traveler.
May I ask your name?
I'm Elaina.
My name is Mirarosé.
Nice to meet you.
Mirarosé, what happened to this town?
I don't know...
You don't?
I don't know what happened
to this town, or why I'm here.
When I woke up, I found myself in
this country that was already in ruins.
Do you have amnesia?
Most likely.
But you remember your name?
"You who are reading this
are the princess, Mirarosé."
You're a princess?
You're living in a room like this in the castle,
so I guess it makes sense.
Oh, okay.
"Why are you here? Why is the country in ruins?
Why have you lost your memory?
I will explain a little.
If you do not want to die, then read this."
Whoever wrote this seems pretty self-important.
It looks like the sun has set.
Right...
"By the way, is it night where you are?
If so, then I'd like you
to look out the window."
Out the window?
What is that?
Continue reading.
"That monster is the demon
that destroyed the country
and the cause of your amnesia.
The monster's name is Javalier."
Is that... Javalier?
The next part of the letter says,
"Awakening as the sun sets,
destroying the country until the sunrise.
Javalier's goal is to annihilate
everyone in this country.
It is going wild looking for the last person--
in other words, you."
Javalier is trying to kill me.
Then, why don't you leave this
country and go somewhere else?
"This castle is safe.
Javalier cannot enter this castle."
Why...?
Who knows?
Besides--
"Javalier is after you, she who has
become a princess without subjects.
If you leave this country,
then Javalier will chase you," it says.
And then finally, it says,
"I'd like to ask you a favor.
I want you to kill Javalier.
As a witch, you should have enough
power to easily defeat Javalier.
Please, for our sake, in order for you to live,
and for the sake of those
unfortunate enough to be killed."
That's how it is.
Huh.
So you're a witch, Mirarosé?
So you're a witch, too, Elaina?
That should've been obvious by my appearance.
I have my brooch on, too.
I'm just kidding.
But that letter leaves a lot of questions.
Why did Javalier appear?
Why were you the only one
to survive and lose your memory?
It doesn't say anything about that.
You're right.
But I'm the princess, and this country
was destroyed by that monster.
So, I have a duty to defeat that.
Don't you agree?
How many days have you seen that monster?
It's the seventh day.
Have you ever fought it?
Not yet.
But, I will fight it tomorrow night.
Do you have any chance of winning?
Of course I do.
You seem very confident.
It's been one week since I woke up,
and I finally remembered how to use magic.
It's possible that before I lost
my memory, I was pretty good.
Moreover, my magic has been recharged.
Do your best.
I will be cheering you on from a safe distance.
Oh my, you won't help me?
Will I gain anything by helping you?
I don't dislike your honesty.
Thanks.
And so, Mirarosé let me use
a room once used by a castle servant.
Now...
It's so fluffy and warm!
Thank you, Mirarosé!
Something smells good...
Good morning.
Morning. These just finished baking.
Where'd they come from?
I baked them.
You can bake?
I can.
Even though you're a princess.
I don't know why, but my
body just seems to remember.
It's mysterious.
Anyway, let's eat while they're still warm.
Let's eat!
It's good.
I'm glad.
Will you listen to me talk
while we eat? About tonight.
You'll be fighting Javalier, right?
I'd like you to help me prepare.
You let me spend the night
and even made breakfast.
I can at least help with your preparations.
Then, will you help me fight Javalier?
Sorry, but no.
Right.
Besides, if this place is safe,
like the letter says,
then don't you have the choice of not fighting?
Well, I suppose the letter's
credibility is also questionable, though.
The resentment the writer of
that letter felt for Javalier is real.
Why do you think that?
I can feel it.
"I hate Javalier so much. I want to kill it."
I can feel that hatred.
And for some reason, I feel the same way.
Well?
Do you think you'll finish by nightfall?
Wh-What does "finish" mean in this case?
Let's see. I think you're maybe halfway done?
I might die first...
Mirarosé's plan is to trick
Javalier into falling into the hole
and then attack with magic
after it is unable to move.
I see.
Even if just prevents a counterattack,
it could be very effective.
The flaw in this plan is that
the preparations are a huge pain.
This is nothing! I'm the Ashen Witch!
This is a trifle!
Thank you for your efforts.
It's almost time.
Let us meet again later.
I'll treat you to a delicious dinner.
No, thank you.
It will be a lot of work for you
to cook after finishing a big job,
I will cook.
So please don't die.
Don't worry. I won't die.
Now, go on.
Until later.
I ended up coming.
It's strange.
Even though I only met her yesterday,
I couldn't help but feel
like I wanted her to live.
So I will fight with her, too.
Without putting my life in danger.
Come now, this way!
Come here, Javalier!
It's here.
She did it!
She's strong.
Maybe I won't need to do anything...
Mirarosé!
So that's how it was.
That's amazing...
Well? Do you understand my despair now?
Goodbye...
...Father.
I remember now.
I got my memories back!
All of them!
She told her father, the king, about how
she had become pregnant with the cook's child.
This is what the king said:
"He will be executed."
The king would not allow their
love that crossed class and rank.
The cook underwent cruel torture,
and was burned to death in front of her eyes.
And the child, too...
I swore
that I would kill everything.
First, in order to make
this castle a safe place,
I put up a barrier that only let mages in.
That's why Javalier
couldn't get into the castle?
And then, I left myself a letter,
and cursed my father,
turning him into a monster.
In exchange, I lost my memories.
Your father, Javalier, destroyed
the country and its people...
Yes, he ate them himself.
On top of that, he did it while
still aware that he was the king.
That monster ate the subjects
whether the king wished to or not.
That should have made
him understand how it felt...
...to have the things dear to
you snatched away from you...
To understand that despair...
Okay, the bread's done.
It's time to eat.
Now, let's eat.
How is it? Is it good?
Really? I'm glad.
It can't compare to the bread you bake, though.
Do you want to eat more?
Oh, look, you've got jam on your cheek.
In this way, the curtain
fell on the "love story"
that all went according to her plan.
She became the princess
without subjects by her own hand...